# **Remy Allard**

# Senior Full Stack Engineer

Denmark
remyallardwork@gmail.com
LinkedIn
Portfolio

I'm a Senior Full Stack Developer specializing in **React.js** and **Django**, with a passion for developing **SaaS** platforms. I'm enthusiastic about learning new frameworks and languages. I place great emphasis on team collaboration and thrive in an agile team environment.

#### **SKILLS**

Languages: JavaScript, TypeScript, Python, Java 11+, C#, SQL, PHP, HTML/CSS

Front End: React.js, Next.js, Angular, Blazor, Vue.js, Bootstrap, Material-UI, Tailwind CSS, SASS, SCSS

Back End: Node.js, Django, FAST-API, Spring Boot, Hibernate, ASP.NET, JPA, Laravel, GraphQL, Shopify, Microservices

Storage: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS DynamoDB, Oracle

**Performance:** Google Analytics, New Relic, Debugging, Cross-browser tools

DevOps: Git, Docker, Heroku, Scrum, Jira, Kubernetes, Gradle, Maven

Cloud Platforms: AWS, Azure, GCP

Others: Communication, Problem-solving, Team Collaboration

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Morning Score, Senior Full Stack Engineer

02/2023 - 05/2024

I played a pivotal role in managing Morning Score, an AI-driven ALL-IN-ONE SEO Tool. My efforts included enhancing the overall UI/UX through the implementation of React.js. Through strategic leadership, I steered our project to achieve competitive performance and capabilities, ensuring its success and prominence in the market.

- Improved overall UX/UI, utilizing React.js and Material UI
- Integrated and managed data from various SEO tools and APIs
- Conducted data preprocessing using rich Python libraries including pandas, Numpy, Matplotlib, scikit-learn
- Communicated with app users to gather feedback to enhance performance and to find the way it will advance
- Integrated payment Gateways to provide Premium features
- Created numerous features among website analysis such as fast scan on related keywords, links and competitors
- Troubleshooted issues within application and bugs in the code base, especially in backend Django project
- Wrote Unit Testing code, using testing libraries like Jest and Django Test
- Utilized Google Analytics to find and optimize performance obstacles in front-end using Amazon CloudFront
- Created CI/CD pipelines, following agile methodologies through the development process using Docker
- Created reusable **React.js** components to ensure front-end scalability based on modularized components
- Used AWS EC2 and AWS S3 to troubleshoot deployment issues
- Contributed to the documentation of Python-based frameworks including Reflex, via various communities and events

## **Roweb**, Senior Full Stack Developer

02/2022 - 01/2023

At Roweb, We developed and optimized web and mobile platforms using a diverse tech stack, implemented security enhancements, and integrated advanced tools to improve user experience and operational efficiency.

- Developed and maintained web components for various e-commerce platforms like <u>Vitalproteins</u> using <u>JQuery</u>,
   HTML/CSS, and Shopify
- Leveraged Google Analytics to optimize SEO performance and address other performance issues for <u>Homex</u>
- Deployed production-ready solutions using Docker, Kubernetes, and cloud services such as AWS and GCP
- Integrated complex tools and features within the **Smart Imobs** platform using **React.js**, **Node.js** and **Bootstrap**
- Implemented social media sharing, responsive design, and blog integration for **Smart Imobs**
- Developed a custom multi-criteria search feature to help visitors find items easily

## Orum, USA, Senior Full Stack Developer

03/2020 - 01/2022

I contributed to the development of an AI-based SAAS startup with keen insight into AI and web technologies, including Node, React, and Django.

- Developed React.js components to display live conversation information between sales members
- Conducted analysis on streaming data to reduce background noise using **Python** libraries
- Worked on Microservices architecture, improving performance like response speed, using Node.js and Django
- Created and Implemented various Dialing and Analysis Scenarios, collaborating with UX/UI designers
- Continuously developed and deployed Orum services, using Docker
- Communicated with app users to gather feedback

# Advanced Web Ranking, Full Stack Developer

04/2018 - 03/2020

My role involved reducing state management errors, launching secure backend services with ASP.NET, Spring Boot and PostgreSQL, and creating web pages using Vue.js.

- Optimized front-end components for rapid development and lightweight design using **Vue.js** and **Vuetify**.
- Implemented Microservices architecture based ASP.NET and Spring Boot for backend scalability and performance
- Created a seamless visualization on businesses ranking, using various UI libraries including D3.js
- Worked in an agile team environment and managed codebase using Git
- Implemented various strategies such as image lazy loading and code splitting to optimize front-end performance

# Kvalifik, Full Stack Developer

03/2016 - 03/2018

- Created and Developed several web applications with React and Webflow
- Designed, Developed and deployed a car selling website for ev-remarketing, utilizing Webflow and Docker

## **Leapwork**, Full Stack Developer

03/2015 - 02/2016

- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to define and implement cutting-edge user experiences in React
- Developed responsive web interfaces using **React**, **Redux Saga**, and SVG animations

## **Morningtrain**, Back End Developer (Intern)

07/2014 - 02/2015

#### **EDUCATION**

# Aalborg University, Copenhagen, Denmark

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Science

09/2011 - 06/2014